#### github.com/billy-le

# **Billy Le**

A skilled software engineer with 4+ years experience and independent thinker looking to tackle modern software development problems using the latest technologies. Seeking to improve development workflow and understanding business requirements by actively engaging in pinpointing the pain problems.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **4insite**, Remote — Lead Front-end Engineer

AUG 2019 - PRESENT

Managed extensive solutions for FE applications to include development tooling, web performance and bundle optimizations. Composed and maintained responsive UI and UX elements to adhere to a strict design system. Lead a small team between 5–10 software engineers on best practices, communicating system changes, and providing constructive feedback through one–on–one mentoring, pair programming and code reviews.

## **SBM Management**, Sacramento, CA — Front-end Engineer

NOV 2018 - AUG 2019

Converted an Angular application into React using best-practices and standards.

## **CLC Inc.**, Roseville, CA — Software Engineer

SEPT 2017 - OCT 2018

Engineered and contributed to various features and internal tools for user surveys and specific edge cases specified by project manager.

## **Freelance**, Sacramento, CA — Full-stack Engineer

APR 2017 - PRESENT

Developed software for clients through a subcontracting company.

#### **EDUCATION**

**freeCodeCamp.org**, Online — *Self-Study* 

APRIL 2016 - JUNE 2018

**Ashford University,** Online — Business Economics, B.A.

IAN 2010 - MAY 2014

#### **SKILLS & PROFICIENCY**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ES6

SASS / PostCSS / TailwindCSS

React, Redux, RxJS

Node, Express

MongoDB

## **PROJECTS**

https://loveedith.netlify.app https://soillife.netlify.app https://4insite-storybook.n etlify.app

#### **AWARDS**

freeCodeCamp Top
Contributor 2018 Officially recognized by the
freeCodeCamp organization
for contributing to my
community